

Faisal Ahmed

P: (571) 409-8514 | **E:** mishu_dc@yahoo.com 4200 CONALLY ST, APT 101, Annandale, VA 22003

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full-stack software developer with 7+ years of experience in web development using **C#.net**, **Asp.net MVC**, **Asp.net Web API**, **Entity Framework**, **React** and **Angular**. 4+ years of experience in Web automation using Selenium WebDriver and Cucumber. Currently looking for a full-time position as a full-stack developer in a challenging environment to utilize my skill and knowledge to the best of my abilities and contribute positively to my personal growth as well as for the growth of the organization.

SKILLS

- C#.net
- Asp.net MVC
- Asp.net Web API
- Entity Framework
- NHibernate
- jQuery
- React

- Angular
- Java
- Selenium WebDriver
- Cucumber
- Visual Studio
- Visual Studio Code
- Git

WORK HISTORY

QA ENGINEER

01/2015 to CURRENT

DrFirst, Inc | Rockville, MD

- Projects: Electronic Prior Authorization, Patient Real Time Benefit Inquiry,
 Gaps in Care, Care Cost Estimator etc.
- Primary role is to automate web interfaces using Selenium WebDriver and Cucumber. API automation using Java, JMeter, Postman and verify user acceptance criteria.
- Worked in a React web portal as a software developer.
- Took the lead role in multiple UATs with Humana, Argus, United Health Group on behalf of DrFirst.
- Played the role of an acting application delivery manager for a short period of time.
- Participated in the myBenefitCheck project for Humana which was reported in Yahoo Finance in 2015

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

04/2011 to 09/2014

XpertLab BD Ltd. | Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Projects: E-Commerce System, Mobile-based Order Capturing System,
 Distribution Management System etc.
- Collaborated with developers, QA, product owner and scrum master to assess requirements, prioritized needs and produced high-quality products.
- Mobile-based Order Capturing System helped one renounced pharmaceutical company to double the number of invoices on month opening.

- Developed a Payroll Management System as a POC within a week to assist the sales team to provide a demo to a client.
- Technology Used: C#.net, Asp.Net MVC, Web API, NHibernate, SQL Server.

PROGRAMMER ANALYST

12/2006 to 03/2010

Computer Ease Ltd. | Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Projects: Humane Resource Management System, Payroll Management System, Distribution Management System.
- Participated in different steps of SDLC.
- Designed and developed application based on requirements using C#.net, Asp.Net, SQL Server, SOAP Services, J2ME.
- Migrated legacy Visual Basic project To C#.net.

EDUCATION

Master of Science | Computer Science United International University, Dhaka

2013

Bachelor of Science | Computer Science and Engineering Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology, Dhaka

2006

CERTIFICATIONS ()

Exam 483: Programming in C#

LINKS ()

Personal Profile: https://faisalahmed.us/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/faisal-ahmed-se/

Git: https://github.com/mishu-dc

Leet Code: https://leetcode.com/mishu_dc/